(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T02:21:24.755460",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と キラメキに乗って☆
With the best time and the best friends, riding on the sparkle☆
(いえいっ！)
Yay!
キラメキライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
みんな今日は来てくれてありがとう！楽しんでってね！
Thanks for coming to see me today, everyone! Have fun!
覚えてるかな？ 最初のうた
Do you remember? That very first song,
私 声が震えていた (ほんのすこし)
my voice was trembling just a little bit.
あの日から続く未来は
The future that started from that day
みんなと掴んだ今日だよ
is today, which we grasped together with everyone.
もっともっともっともっともっと加速するハート
A heart accelerating more and more!
(いっしょに) 行くよ どこまでも
Let's go together, no matter where!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK！？
Are you ready? Is preparation OK?
ひらけ！！夢の扉を (いち に さん)
Open wide the door of dreams! (One, two, three!)
(キラメキライダー☆)
Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
With the best time and the best friends, I'm right here because you found me.
きみに会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I wanted to see you, so I came. Let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
とどいてるかな？ 私の声 (はっきりと)
Can you hear it? My voice...
届けたいのは きみに笑顔 (そのスマイル！)
I want to deliver my smiling face to you!
理想のトナリに悔しくて
Regretful about the ideal path,
みんなと泣き笑ったね
we cried and laughed together, didn't we?
ぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとぎゅっとすべて抱きしめて
Tightly, tightly, tightly, embracing everything!
(いっしょに) 行こう どこまでも
Let's go together, no matter where!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK！？
Are you ready? Is preparation OK?
すすめ！！希望の道を (いち に さん)
Press forward along the path of hope! (One, two, three!)
(キラメキライダー☆)
Kirameki Rider☆
好きな気持ち カラフルに奏でたいな
I want to play my favorite feelings in full color.
最高の場所 最高のみんなと
With the best place and the best everyone,
ここにいるよ まぶるしなんかないじゃない
I'm right here, so don't be shy at all!
きみの心が幸せに染まるように
So that your heart is dyed with happiness,
かさねてくハーモニィ キラメキ纏って☆
add a harmony, wrapped in sparkles☆
うたいつづけたいな おどりつづけたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing.
そんな願いやワガママもいいでしょ？
Is such a wish or selfishness okay?
だって楽しすぎて！もう止まらない！！
Because it's too fun! It won't stop anymore!
輝くステージで もっともっと！！ (お願いい) ずっと！！
On a shining stage, more and more! (Please!) Forever!
うれしい 楽しい いとおしい だけじゃ語れない
Happy, joyful, and lovely... words alone aren't enough.
いまも いまも 悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, I still have worries, but
ここにいるよ 私 ここにいるよ
I am right here, I am right here,
きみと同じ世界を見つめてて
looking at the same world as you.
(いくよ！) キラメキライダー☆
(Let's go!) Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo out!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
With the best time and the best friends, I'm right here because you found me.
きみに会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう (せーの)
I wanted to see you, so I came. Let's sing together!
終わらないメロディ キラメキに乗って☆
An endless melody, riding on the sparkle☆
キラメキ纏って☆
Wrapped in sparkles☆
生まれ立てのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats resound!
最高な時間 最高な仲間と キラメキに乗って☆
With the best times and best friends, riding on the sparkle!
(いぇーーい!)
(Yeah!)
おぼえてるかな? さ最初のうた
Do you remember? Our very first song
(なつかしいね)
(How nostalgic)
私の声が震えていた
My voice was trembling
(ほんのすこし)
(Just a little)
あの日から続く未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなで掴んだ今日だよ
Is today we grasped together with everyone
もっともっともっともっともっと加速するハート
Accelerating more and more and more and more, my heart
(いっしょに)いくよどこまでも
(Together) Let's go anywhere!
(Are you ready?) 準備はOK?
(Are you ready?) Is everything ready?
ひらけ!! 夢の扉を
Open up!! The door of dreams
(いち に さん)
(One, two, three)
(キラメキラライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
ありがとう！
Thank you!
キラメキライダーでしたー！
That was Kirameki Rider!
というわけで、
So, everyone...
みなさーーん！ こんばみおーー！
Everyone! Good evening Mio!
おおかみみおでーす！
I'm Ookami Mio!
あ、みんなすごい！ 2周年をお祝いしてくれて本当にどうもありがとう！
Ah, you're amazing! Thank you so much for celebrating my 2nd anniversary!
ちょっと1曲目からね、激しめの曲だったので少し息が上がっておりますが、あ！
Since the first song was quite intense, I'm a bit out of breath, but ah!
あの、ちょっとお漏らししちゃいましたね。すみません。
Um, I kind of made a slip of the tongue. Sorry about that.
あ、ぱちぱちありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you for the applause!
いや、2周年ありがとうございます。本当に応援してくれる皆さんのおかげで3年目をこれからも歩み出そうとしております。
Yeah, thank you so much for the 2nd anniversary. Thanks to everyone supporting me, I'm about to step into my 3rd year.
ちょっとね、あの、これからも曲続くんですけれどもしょ、ちょいちょいこうMCを挟みながらみんなと今日は楽しんでいけたらいいなと思っておりますので、どうぞよろしくお願いいたします！
Um, there are more songs coming up, but I hope to chat with you all via MCs along the way and enjoy today together, so I look forward to it!
というわけで、さあ、すぐ2曲目いっちゃおうかな。ちょっとお漏らししちゃったけど。じゃあ、2曲目お願いしまーす！
With that said, let's head straight into the second song. Even though I made a slip earlier. Well then, hit the second song, please!
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
だって本当はcrazy
Because we're actually crazy
白鳥たちはそう 見えないところでバタ足するんです
White swans are actually paddling furiously where you can't see
本能に順従 忠実 翻弄も重々承知 前途洋々だし...
Obedient to instinct, faithful, fully aware of getting carried away, our future is bright, so...
だからたまに休業しちゃうんです
That's why we take a break every now and then.
この目でしかり見定めて 行き先地図上マークして
Stare closely with your own eyes, mark the destination on the map
近道あればそれが王道 はしゃる翼があれば上等
If there's a shortcut, that's the royal road; if you have wings to flutter, that's top-notch
ヤマブツメ割れた グルーで補修した
The hairpin broke, repaired it with glue
それだけでなんか達成感 大事なのは自分かわいがること
Just that gives a sense of achievement; what's important is loving yourself
自分を愛さなきゃ 他人も愛せない
If you don't love yourself, you can't love others either
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
だって本当はcrazy
Because we're actually crazy
梟たちはそう 見えないところにピック隠すんです
Owls secretly hide their picks where you can't see
想像に一生懸命 現実絶体絶命 発展途上だし...
Putting everything into imagination, reality is desperate, still in progress, so...
だからたまにピッチ外れるんです
That's why we occasionally go off pitch.
その目に映らないだけだって やる気はメーター振り切って
It's just that it doesn't show in your eyes, motivation maxes out the meter
いつでも全力で夢見て その分全力で眠って
Always dreaming with all our might, sleeping with all our might accordingly
ヤリッチオイヤセタ 調子づいてくった
Got a bit skinny, got carried away and stuffed myself
それだけでなんで? 敗北感 すかさず目標 下方修正して
Just for that? A sense of defeat; immediately revising targets downward
柔軟に臨機応変 七変化が勝ち
Flexible and adaptable, shape-shifting wins
Please don’t say “You are lazy”
だって本当はcrazy
Because we're actually crazy
孔雀たちはそう ここぞというとき美を魅せるんです
Peacocks show their beauty precisely when it counts
五臓六腑 全身邁進 願望は痩身美人
Viscera, moving forward with all one's might, desire is a slender beauty
誘惑多発だし... だからやけに意志砕けちゃうんです
Temptations are frequent, so willpower easily shatters
愛 愛 愛 愛
Love, love, love, love
おうちはめちゃ楽しんでるよー！
I'm having so much fun at home!
ヤバ まさかレボイ？
Oh crap, could it be?
いや ギリクリア！
No, barely cleared it!
それだけで なんて全能感
That alone gives me omnipotence!
大事なのは自分 認めてくこと
The most important thing is accepting yourself.
自分を許さないと 他人も許せない
If you don't forgive yourself, you can't forgive others.
Please don't say "You are lazy" だって本当はcrazy
Please don't say "You are lazy" 'cause it'll drive me crazy.
白鳥たちはそう 見えないところでバタ足するんです
Yeah, even graceful swans paddle where you can't see.
本能に順従 忠実 翻弄も御高承
Following instincts faithfully, fully aware of the turns.
だからたまに休息しちゃうんです
So I take a break every once in a while.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
わぁ！2周年お祝いのケーキだ！嬉しい！
Wow! An anniversary cake! I'm so happy!
いただきまーす！
Let's dig in!
うん、甘くって美味しい！
Mmm, it's sweet and delicious!
もう一口...んー、最高だね！
Another bite... mmm, simply the best!
美味し、美味しい...もう一口！
So good, so good... one more bite!
いや、これは...これはもう、クリームですね！
Man, this is... this is pure cream!
美味しい！みんなも食べたいでしょ？
Delicious! You guys want some too, right?
あーん、あげないけどね！んー、もう一口！
Ahh—not giving you any, though! Mmm, another bite!
あ、もうラスト行くか！もう一口、んー...
Ah, time for the last piece! One more bite, mmm...
完食！ごちそうさまでした！
Finished! Thank you for the meal!
雪が舞い散る夜空 二人寄り添い見上げた
The night sky where snow dances down, we looked up together.
繋がる手と手の温もりは とても優しかった
The warmth of our connected hands was so gentle.
淡いオールドブルーの 雲間に消えていくでしょう
Fading away into the gaps of pale old-blue clouds.
永遠へと続くはずの あの約束
That promise that was supposed to last forever.
あなたの傍にいるだけで ただそれだけで良かった
Just being by your side, simply that was enough.
いつの間にか膨らむ 今以上の夢に気付かずに
Without realizing a dream growing larger than before.
どんな時も どこにいる時も 強く強く 抱きしめていて
No matter when or where, hold me tight and close.
あなたへのこの想いは全て 終わりない と信じている
Believing these feelings for you will never end.
貴方だけ ずっと見つめているの
Only you, I am gazing at you forever.
交わす言葉と時間 姿を変えていくでしょう
Exchanged words and time will change their form.
白い頬に解けた それは月の涙
Melting on pale cheeks, those are the moon's tears.
行かないでで少しだけ 何度も言いかけては また会えるよねきっとなつ
Trying to say "Don't go, just a little more" over and over, surely we'll meet again.
雪が舞い散る夜空
The night sky where snow dances down,
二人寄り添い見上げた
looking up together side by side.
繋ぐ手と手の温もりは
The warmth of our hands holding on
とても優しかった
was so gentle.
淡いオールドブルーの
In the pale old-blue
雲間に消えていくのでしょう
clouds, fading away...
どんなときもどこにいるときも
No matter when, no matter where I am,
強く強く抱きしめていて
hold me tight and embrace me strongly.
情熱が日常に染まるとしても
Even if passion becomes dyed by everyday life,
あなたへのこの想いは全て終わりなどないと信じている
I believe this feeling for you will never come to an end.
貴方だけずっと見つめているの
I am gazing only at you, always.
交わする言葉と時間
The words and time we exchanged
姿を変えていくのでしょう
will change their forms, won't they?
白い頬に溶けたそれは月の涙
Melting on white cheeks, those are the moon's tears.
「行かないで、もう少しだけ」
"Don't go, just a little longer..."
何度も呼びかけては
I called out to you over and over,
「また会えるよね、きっと」
"We'll meet again for sure..."
何度も自分に問いかける
I asked myself that again and again.
突然走り出した行く先の違う二人
Suddenly we started running on different paths,
もう止まらない沈黙が走馬灯を越え引き裂いて
no longer stopping, silence tearing through memories past.
ひとつだけ許される願いがあるなら
If there is just one wish allowed to me,
ごめんねと伝えたいよいくら想っていても届かない
I want to say "I'm sorry", though no matter how I feel it won't reach you.
声にしなきゃ動き出さなくちゃ隠したままの二人の秘密このまま忘れられてしまうの
If I don't give it a voice, if I don't start moving, will our hidden secret be forgotten just like this?
だからね早く今ここに来て
That's why, please come here quickly now.
あなたへのこの想いは全て終わりなどないと信じている貴方だけずっと見つめているの
I believe this feeling for you will never end, I am gazing only at you, always.
ふぅー、お疲れ様でした！
Phew, good work to me!
生だから、生だから
It's live, so it's live!
ここで、あの、すいません、あの
Right here, um, sorry, um...
ちょっとこんな、こんなこと、こんなことになった後なんですけど、あの、ゲストがいます！
After something like this, something like this happened, um, we have a guest!
えーーー！
Ehhhh!
おーい！おーい！きつねやーい！
Hey! Hey! Fox-san!
あ、いた！
Ah, there!
こんなとこにいた！きつね！
You were in a place like this! Fox!
どうにかしてくれこの空気！もうどうしよううち！
Do something about this atmosphere! What should I do?!
歌う、歌う前の転換の時にさ、よけきれんくって食ってからさ
During the transition before singing, I couldn't dodge it and ate it...
やっちまった！
I messed up!
跳び跳ねるとか言いながらあげるもしてくれなかったから
Saying we'd jump around and stuff, but you didn't even give me anything...
ごめん、ごめん、うちが全部一人で済んじゃったから
Sorry, sorry, because I finished it all by myself!
大丈夫だみお、あの、みおだってほら、足元雪だからさ、ケーキ白いからわかる
It's okay Mio, I mean Mio too, look, your feet are in snow, and the cake is white so you can tell...
余計わかるだろ、お前は！
That makes it even more obvious, you idiot!
それはわかるよ！
That's obvious!
わかんない、見えない、見えない。
I don't know, I can't see, I can't see.
わかんないかな？見えない、見えない、大丈夫、大丈夫。うん。
You can't tell? I can't see, I can't see, it's fine, it's fine. Yeah.
あの、入ってはいないんですよ。
Um, it didn't actually go in, you know.
入ってないね。
It didn't go in, right?
ちょっとこう見上げた
You looked up a bit...
後ろからもう、みおが咳き込ん、みお！って、大丈夫かって声が出ちゃったもんなんだよ。
From behind, Mio started coughing and I went "Mio!" out loud, asking if she was okay.
リハーサルはうまく行ってたんだ。
Rehearsals went so well.
そう、リハーサルはね、よかったんだけどね、ケーキ食うから、リハーサル食ってなかったやん、ケーキ。
Yeah, rehearsals were great, but because we ate cake, we didn't eat cake during rehearsal.
そうだね、あそこで食うからだよ！
That's right, because you eat it there!
まあまあ、これもね、あの、奈良では、奈良では
Well, well, this too, um, in Nara, in Nara...
そうだね、みおはうまくいったよ！
That's right, Mio did great!
ちょっとあれはね、ちょっとえぐいやつやっちゃったね。
That was a pretty brutal thing we did.
カットされるかもしれないね、これ普通にね、放送してる時だったらボリューム絞ってるレベルの咳だった。
It might get cut, normally if we were broadcasting live, that was a cough level where you'd turn down the volume.
そうだね、ちょんだね、そうですね。
That's right, haha, exactly.
はい、というわけで、本日、え、毎年ね、うちがね、周年になると現れてくれる白上フブキさんにお越しいただきました！
Yes, so today, um, Shirakami Fubuki-san, who always appears every year when it's my anniversary, came to visit us!
はーい、白上フブキでーす。
Hii, I'm Shirakami Fubuki.
ありがとう！この「日」っていう文字がシャープの半分みたいに見える。
Thank you! This character "Hi" looks kind of like half of a sharp sign.
本当だ、なかなかね、あの、見ないフォントだよね。
True, it's quite a rare font to see.
そうだね、紙のとこもなんか短めだしさ、まあでも可愛い可愛いフォントね。はい。
Yeah, and the paper part is also kind of short, but well, it's a cute font. Yes.
というわけでね、えー、まあ、ちょっとね、二周年記念ということで、え、ライブの...
So, um, yeah, as it's the 2nd anniversary, um, the live...
ねえ 見よ
Hey, Mio.
早いね！ 早いね 二周年 あっという間だったね
It's so fast! The 2nd anniversary went by in a flash.
そうなんだよ。
Yeah, that's right.
でね、ここでね、みおへのお手紙みたいな感じで仲そうかと思ったんだけど、今回また
And you know, I thought about exposing Mio's handwritten letters...
まただからね！
Wait, wait, that's why!
さすがにそういうわけにはいかないと思って
I thought we shouldn't do something like that...
このあとズビズビになっちゃう。
And then it gets super awkward!
そうそうこのあとズビズビしながらね、 まだまだ曲流してるのにってなっちゃうんだけど
Like, we're still in the middle of reading songs, and you're like...
そうだね。
Oh, I see.
いや、もうホントに改めて見よう。 二周年おめでとう！
Well, let's do it properly! Happy 2nd anniversary!
やったー！ ありがとう！ 嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
おめでとう！ ありがとう！ おめでとう！
Happy anniversary, congratulations!
ねえ、1曲目からキラメキライダーぶち込んできたね。
You managed to drop the "Kirameki Rider" right from the first song.
いや、なんか最初ぶち上げたくて。
Well, I wanted to blow it up right at the beginning.
そう、後ろで白上もね、ずっとあの、しーしーってしてたんだけどね、声が入らないように頑張ってました。
And in the background, Shirakami was like, "Shh, shh," making sure no voice got in.
やあ、そうやね。
Yeah, that's right.
もうなんか最初から参加してもらおうかとも思ったんだけどね。
I even thought about having you participate from the very beginning.
あ、もう二周年記念で現れる厄介オタクみたいになっちゃうからさ、あ、のって厄介オタクね。
If it appears on the 2nd anniversary, you'd look like an annoying otaku, so I thought, "No, annoying otaku, right?"
そうそう。
That's right.
「やったー！」みたいなキラメキライダー！
Like "Yay!", being Kirameki Rider-ish.
キラメキライダー！ 厄介オタク、おい、やめろ、みおのライブだぞって怒られちゃうんだよ、みおさんにね。
"Kirameki Rider!" (Annoying otaku, hey, stop it, Mio's live-as-you-go!)
いや、でもさ、でもさ
Yeah, but you know...
ふぶきと一緒にカラオケ行ったことあるよね？
Fubuki, we've done karaoke together before, right?
あるあるある！
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
なんかその時はさ、割と、あの、あいのてマスターだったよね。
And back then, you were pretty much an "Ah, note" master, weren't you?
いや、なかったね！ ちょっとね、反省をした。
I wasn't! I had to reflect a bit.
反省をしました、白上は。
I made Shirakami reflect on it.
で、1曲目がDon't say "lazy"。なんでこれ選んだの、みおん？
And the first song was Don't Say Lazy. Why did you choose that one, Mio?
あ、
Ah...
なんか歌いたいなって思っただけ。
I just felt like singing it, that's all.
それだけ？
Just that?
そう。
Yeah.
カラオケかよ！
It's karaoke!
いや、でもカラオケだよ！ でも、やっぱかっこいいの似合うよね、みおん。
Well, karaoke is great too!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Don't say "lazy" めっちゃよかったもん。
Don't Say Lazy was really good.
Don't say "lazy"と、あと「深愛」に関してはですね、カラオケの音源を作ってもらいまして、
And about Don't Say Lazy and Shin'ai, Mio had the karaoke audio made for them.
作ってもらったんだ？
You had it made?
そうなんですよう、だからね、概要欄のね、スペシャルサンクスの方にもね、書いてあるんですけれども、
Yes, that's right. It's written in the special thanks in the description box, too.
作っていただいた方のね、URLも載せてますので。
We've credited the person who made it for us.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
Don't say "lazy"ちょっとね、事故った「深愛」だけどもう
And Don't Say Lazy had a bit of a botched "Shin'ai" moment...
事故った「深愛」じゃ、やめろ！
A botched "Shin'ai"? Stop it!
事故った「深愛」って言うな！
A botched "Shin'ai", come on!
事故った「深愛」はちょっと声が悪いぞ。
A botched "Shin'ai" sounded a bit bad, though.
確かに。まあ、深愛だけどもう
True, true. But "Shin'ai" alone...
ねえ、まさかこの曲持ってくるとは思わなくて私びっくりした。
I was so surprised that you brought this song.
あー！
Ah...
なんか水樹奈々さんの曲すごい、いいなと思って。
Mizuki Nana's songs are really good, aren't they?
いいよね、かっこいいよね！
They're so cool!
そう、なんだけど、なかなかこうカラオケの音源がなかったりするから、なんか今回こういう機会で作っちゃおうかなって思って。
Yeah, but it's hard to find karaoke audio for them sometimes, so I thought I'd have one made this time.
おお、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
だから好きな曲だから作ってもらったんだよね。
Since it's my favorite song, I had it made.
いやあ、いいね！ 深愛。 めっちゃよかった。
Yeah, it's great! Shin'ai was really good.
はい。
Well...
まあ、ちょっと事故っちゃったけど。
I mean, I kind of messed up, though.
事故ってなんぼのライブだと思ったの、全然気にしてないよ。
Saying you "messed up" on a live anniversary stream, no way!
むしろ、そうそう、むしろね、もっとせき込んでコンコンしてもろて。
On the contrary, let's cram more in and go honk-honk!
ああ、オッケー。
Oh, okay.
なんなんだろうね、なんかね、突然出てきちゃったんだよね、なんか、もう耐えられなくて。
What could it be? It just suddenly came out, you know.
いや、多分ね、緊張とともにさ、そう、ちょっと声もね、詰まっちゃうんだよね。
Well, probably with the tension, your throat gets a bit tight too.
そうなんだよねー。
Yeah, that's right.
ねえ、みんないっぱい見てるからね、ほらだって。
Because everyone is watching so much, right? Horahora.
そう、そうそう、緊張するからね、やっぱりね。
So you get nervous, of course.
もうなんかさ、ステージでさ、こういうのってさ、するのって言うのが初めてでさ。
Like, singing on stage like that, it's the first time, right?
そうよね。
That's right, yeah.
おお。
Yeah.
いや、いいね！ すごいよね。
Oh, that's amazing.
みおにね、そんなね、みおにちょっとリラックス体操をね教えようかなって
So, Mio, I want to teach you a relaxation exercise.
白上式リラックス体操をしようかなと思いますので、
A Shirakami-style relaxation exercise.
じゃあ白上に合わせちょっと体動かしてもらっていいですか？
So could you move your body along with Shirakami?
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
はい、はい、今からじゃね。
Alright, let's do it now.
両手を上げて、ゆらゆら揺れる、みおん、みおん、
Raise both hands and sway, sway, sway, Mio, Mio!
みおん、みおん、ゆらゆらゆらゆらみおん、みおん、
Mio, sway, sway, sway, myon, myon!
オッケー、リラックス！
Okay, relax!
絶対即席で作っただろ、これ！
You definitely made that up on the spot!
即席で作って！
Instantly made!
いやでもね、これで体の力抜いてね、
Well, you gotta relax your body, right?
そうそうそうそう、ゆらゆらゆらみおん、みおん、
Sway, sway, sway, myon, myon!
天才か？
Are you a genius?
いや、天才だよ、白上は。
I'm a genius, Shirakami is.
ライブの天才って言われてるらしいからね、
They say the genius of the live...
天才きっつね。
You're a genius lately, huh?
自称天才きっつね。
Self-proclaimed genius kittsune.
自称だっ。
Self-proclaimed?
自称天才きっつね、やめろ！
Self-proclaimed genius kittsune, stop it!
やばい、なんかふぶきとこのまま喋ってると、このまま1時間過ぎちゃうし。
Wait, if Fubuki and I keep talking like this, an hour will fly by!
それ！
Right?
まずいまずいまずいまずい。みおのね、ちょっとお祝いということで改めてみおん本当におめでとう！
First of all, first of all, first of all, it's Mio's anniversary, so let's properly celebrate! Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いやあ、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Thank you so much!
ねえ、3年目のみおん、3年目のみおん、
Here's to Mio's 3rd year— I mean 3rd year of Mio!
ねえ。 はい、よろしくお願いいたします。
Right. Well, we look forward to your continued support!
皆さんよろしくお願いします。
Please treat us well, everyone.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Yes, please.
ということでね、ここからもまだまだね、トークが残ってますので、
So from here on, there are still plenty of talk segments, right?
みおはなの皆様は全力でいろいろと振ってもらってね。
Mio-hana, everyone, please throw everything you've got at us!
サイレムバーカー振ってもらって、
Throw us super chats like crazy!
はい、そして、そしてね、みおのスクショでいっぱい、いっぱい撮ってください。
And please take lots and lots of screenshots of Mio!
撮ってください。
Please do!
よろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to it!
そしてね、右上にありますハッシュタグ＃大神ミオ2周年でぜひともTwitter
And please check out the hashtag #OokamiMio2ndAnniversary on Twitter.
それ、それそれ、それみおん届く？って届く？おりゃ！
Does it reach? Does it reach? Orya!
動いた？
Did I move it?
普通にいただいた。ね、たくさんズビズビ送ってください。
Well, you got plenty, so please send lots of super chats!
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
というわけでね、ふぶきはね、またちょっとのちほどちょっとだけ登場してもらうかなと思ってるんだけど。
That being said, Fubuki will step out for a bit and join us again later for a little while.
はい！
Yes!
はい、この後また見守り係りに入ってもらおうかなと思います。はい、見守り係りです！
Right, after this, we'll have her on lookout duty, I think! Yes, lookout duty!
本当にいつもありがとうね！
Thank you so much, as always!
いやいや、ありがとう、みおも！
Yeah, thank you, Mio!
昨日のポップコーンも良かったよ。
Yesterday's popcorn was great too.
あれは黒歴史だよ！
That's black history!
やめてくれ！
Stop it!
あの企画が黒歴史みたいな。やめてくれ！
It's like that project was black history. Stop it!
そんなことない、第2回もやります！
No such thing, we'll do a second time too!
あー、頑張ってねー！
Oh, good luck!
はーい、ありがとうございましたー！
Yeah, thank you very much!
サラダバー！サラダバー！
Salad bar! Salad bar!
はい、というわけで、白上フブキはこのまま見守り体制に入っていただきますが、
So, Shirakami Fubuki will stay for this watching defense.
この後、えーっと、うちは、えー、
after this, um, we...
別の曲が始まりますので、
a different song will start, so...
ちょっとね、お水飲んでね。
We'll get some water, because...
みんなもね、本当にどうもあり…
Everyone, thank you so much for coming.
今日さ、すごい、いっぱいさ、
Today, wow, so...
メンバー入ってくれてる人いてさ、すごいびっくりした。
There were people coming in as members, I was really surprised.
ありがとね！スパチャもありがとうございます、本当に！
Thank you! Thank you so much for the super chats!
あの、後ほどね、チャットを読みながら雑談とかもしようかと思っておりますので、
I'm thinking of chatting while watching later, so...
本当にありがとうございます。
thank you very much.
はい。
Yeah.
うーん、うーん、うーん！
Um, um, um!
あー、チューニング、チューニング！あー、あー！
Ah, tuning, tuning! Ah, ah!
あー、はい、というわけで、
Ah, yes, so...
えー、では、これからのミオのライブ、
Um, now, Mio's live...
もうちょっとだけ続くんだよお！
will continue a bit longer!
では次の曲もよろしくお願いします！
So please look forward to the next song!
粉雪 舞う 季節 は
The season of fluttering powdered snow,
いつも すれ違い
we always pass each other by.
人ごみ に 紛れ て も
Though lost in the crowd,
同じ 空 見 てる の に
we look at the same sky.
風 に 吹かれ て 似た よう に 凍える の に
Blown by the wind, freezing alike,
僕 は 君 の すべて など 知って は い ない だろう
I probably don't know everything about you,
それでも 一億人 から 君 を 見つけた よ
yet I found you out of a hundred million people.
根拠 は ない けど 本気 で 思って いる ん だ
I have no proof, but I truly believe it.
些細 な 言い合い も なく て
Without even minor quarrels,
同じ 時間 を 生きて なんか いけない
living through the same time,
素直 に なれない なら
if we cannot be honest,
喜び も 悲しみ も 虚しい だけ
joy and sorrow are both empty.
粉雪 ねえ 心 まで 白く 染め られた なら
Powdered snow, if our hearts were dyed white,
二人 の 孤独 を 分け合う こと が できた の かい
could we share our loneliness?
僕 は 君 の 心 に 耳 を 押し当て て
I press my ear to your heart,
その 声 の する 方 へ すっと 深く まで 降りて ゆきたい
and descend quietly into the depths where your voice leads.
そこ で もう一度 会おう
Let's meet there once again.
分かり合いたい なんて 上辺 を 撫でて いた の は 僕 の 方
I was the one who wanted to understand each other,
君 の かじかんだ 手 も 握りしめる こと だけ で 繋がって いた のに
yet we could connect just by holding your cold hands.
粉雪 ねえ 永遠 を 前 に あまりに 脆く
Powdered snow, too fragile before eternity,
ざわつく アスファルト の 上 染み に なって ゆく よ
it stains the rough asphalt.
粉雪 ねえ 時 に 頼りなく 心 は 揺れる
Powdered snow, sometimes my heart sways,
それでも 僕 は 君 の こと 守り 続けたい
even so, I want to keep protecting you.
粉雪 ねえ 心 まで 白く 染め られた なら
Powdered snow, if our hearts were dyed white,
二人 の 孤独 を 包ん で 空 に かえす から
it would wrap our loneliness and return it to the sky.
粉雪舞う季節はいつまでもすれ違い
The season when powder snow dances is always passing us by,
人混みに紛れても同じ空見てるのに
Even lost in the crowd, we're looking at the same sky.
風に吹き払れて 似たように凍えるのに
Blowing in the wind, freezing just the same,
僕は君のすべてなど知ってはいないだろう
I suppose I don't know everything about you.
それでも一億人から君を見つけたよ
Even so, I found you out of a hundred million people.
根拠はないけど本気で思ってるんだ
I have no proof, but I believe it in my heart.
心は揺れる
My heart trembles.
それでも僕は君のこと守り続けたい
Even so, I want to keep protecting you.
粉雪ねえ 心まで白く染められたなら
If the powder snow could dye our hearts in white,
二人の孤独を分かち合うことができたのかい
Could we share our solitude?
その声のする方へとすっと深くまで下りてゆきたい そこでもう一度会おうか
I want to descend to where your voice is, and meet you there once more.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ちょっとね、
Well then...
一回ちょっぴり休憩を挟ませてもらおうかな。
Let's take a little break here.
いいよ! すいませんでした!
Ah, I'm so sorry!
本当にすいませんでした! 何かこう始まってしまいましたね、咳から。
Really, I'm so sorry, somehow this just started all of a sudden.
始まってしまいましたか? はい。
It started already? Yes.
ちょっとじゃあ、ちょっぴり休憩をさせていただいて、
So, let's take a short break,
その間にちょっと何かこう、きっと何かが変わると思うので。
and during that time, something will definitely change, I think.
何かが変わって...
Something changes...
ステージも変わって、うちも変わると思います。
The stage will change, and my outfit will change too, I think.
なので、ちょっと皆さんね、ちょっとだけ休憩をもらってもいいですか?
So everyone, could you please take a little break?
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
梅さん? そうですね、ちょっとあの動画を流してくれるそうなので、皆さんそちらを、どうぞ!
Ume-san? Right, they're going to stream the video, so everyone, please check that out!
あー! 2周年お祝いのケーキだ! 嬉しい!
Ah, it's a 2nd-anniversary cake! I'm so happy!
いただきます!
Let's dig in!
甘くて美味しい!
It's sweet and delicious.
もういっちょ、あん、あん...
Let's have another bite. Yum, yum...
あー、最高だね!
Ah, this is the best!
美味しい、美味しい。
Delicious, delicious.
あ、いや、これは、これは、これはもう、これクリーミーですねー!
Ah, now this... this is so creamy!
美味しい! 皆さんも食べたいでしょ?
It's so good! Everyone wants some too, right?
あー、あげないけどね。
Ah, I won't give it to you though.
んー、もういっちょ。
Mmm, another bite.
あ、もうラスト1口だ! もういっこう。
Ah, just one more bite and I'll finish it! Okay, one more.
んー、完食! おかわりゅう!
Mmm, finished! Thank you for the meal!
あー! 2周年お祝いのケーキだ! 嬉しい!
Ah, it's a 2nd-anniversary cake! I'm so happy!
いただきます!
Let's dig in!
甘くて美味しい!
It's sweet and delicious.
もういっちょ、あん、あん...
Let's have another bite. Yum, yum...
あー、最高だね!
Ah, this is the best!
美味しい、美味しい。
Delicious, delicious.
あ、いや、これは、これは、これはもう、これクリーミーですねー!
Ah, now this... this is so creamy!
美味しい! 皆さんも食べたいでしょ?
It's so good! Everyone wants some too, right?
あー、あげないけどね。
Ah, I won't give it to you though.
んー、もういっちょ。
Mmm, another bite.
あ、もうラスト1口だ! もういっこう。
Ah, just one more bite and I'll finish it! Okay, one more.
んー、完食! おかわりゅう!
Mmm, finished! Thank you for the meal!
あれからぼくたちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, have we been able to believe in something?
夜空の向こうには 明日がもう待っている
Beyond the night sky, tomorrow is already waiting.
誰かの声に気づき ぼくらは身をひそめた
We hid ourselves, noticing someone's voice,
公園のフェンス越しに 夜の風が吹いた
And the night wind blew past the park fence.
君が何か伝えようと 握り返したその手は
The hand that you gripped back to tell me something
ぼくの心の やわらかい場所を 今でもまだしめつける
Still grips the softest part of my heart even now.
あれからぼくたちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, have we been able to believe in something?
マドをそっと開けてみる 冬の風のにおいがした
Softly opening the window, I smelled the winter wind.
悲しみだっていつかは 消えてしまうものなのかな
I wonder if sadness is something that eventually fades away.
タメ息は少しだけ 白く残ってすぐ消えた
A sigh lingered white for a moment and quickly vanished.
歩き出すことさえも いちいちためらうくせに
Even though I hesitate at every single step,
つまらない常識など つぶせると思ってた
I thought I could crush trivial common sense.
君に話した言葉は どれだけ残っているの?
How much of what I told you is still left?
ぼくの心の一番 奥でからまわりしつづける
Spinning endlessly in the deepest part of my heart.
あのころの未来に ぼくらは立っているのかな
Are we standing in the future of those days?
全てが思うほど うまくはいかないみたいだ
It seems not everything goes as well as we thought.
このままどこまでも 日々は続いていくのかな
Will these days continue on like this forever?
雲のない星空が マドのむこうにつづいている
A cloudless starry sky stretches beyond the window.
あれからぼくたちは 何かを信じてこれたかな
Since then, have we been able to believe in something?
夜空の向こうには 明日がもう待っている
Beyond the night sky, tomorrow is already waiting.
え、ところ変わって ここはビルの屋上となっております。
Um, changing locations, we are now on top of a building rooftop.
まあちょっとですね、あの、ま、夜景で大人っぽく、夜空の向こうでね、行こうかなと。
Well, you know, with a night view, trying to look mature, beyond the night sky...
お耳ありがとうございます、うちらかみさん。えー。
Thank you for listening, Uchira-kamisan. Uh...
へへ そういう感じで えへへ
Heh. Well, something like that...
歌わせていただきました! 空の向こうありがとうございましたー!
I got to sing it for you! Thank you beyond the skies!
ありがとーー!
Thank you!
というわけで、えー そうですね、ま、ちょっともうちょっとかっこいい曲歌ってもいいんじゃないかな、と思って
So, um... I thought about singing an even cooler song this time,
もう1曲選曲してみたんですけどこの夜景のバックでもう1曲皆さんにはかっこいい大神ミオを見せたいと思います
and I picked this one, but with this night view, I wanted to show you all a really cool Ookami Mio!
へへっ
Hehe.
ちょっとつまずいちゃったりもしたけど今回はちゃんとビシッと決めたいなって、頑張りたいなって思ってますので見守りよろしくお願いします!
I tripped up a bit, but this time I really want to nail it and give it my all, so I'd appreciate your continued support!
はい。
Yes.
あ、すごい!今散らかりふぶきお水かかりにTwitterのトレンド入りになってるって教えてもらった!
Ah, wow! Right now, my stray sparks are making it onto the Twitter trends!
ありがとーみんなー!
Thank you, everyone!
つぶやきありがとーー!
Thank you for your tweets!
というわけでね、皆さんのねつぶやき後で巡回しようと思ってますのでスクショなどもね、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
And so, I'm going to round up everyone's tweets later, so please make sure to use screenshots and stuff, okay?
というわけで、えーちょっとかっこいい大神ミオをえー見せれるといいなと思っておりますので皆さんぜひ次の曲も楽しみにしててくださいね!盛り上がっていくぞ!
So, I'm hoping to show you a really cool Ookami Mio, so everyone, please look forward to the next song! Let's get hyped!
おーー!
Woo!
というわけで、運営さんよろしくお願いします!
And management-san, please take care of us!
旅のはじまりは もう思い出せない
I can no longer remember the start of this journey.
気づいたら ここにいた
Before I realized, I was already here.
季節が破れて 未発見赤外線 感じる目が 迷子になる
As the seasons wore away, those who sense the invisible infrared rays become lost.
たぶん失うのだ 命がけの想い
I will probably lose them, these feelings that I risk my life for.
戦うように恋した
I loved as if I were fighting to survive.
ひたむきに夢を掘った
I spent all my time building my dream.
その星に降りたかった 君の空飛びたかった
I wanted to land on that star. I wanted to fly in your sky.
誰か空虚の輪郭を そっと撫でてくれないか
Wouldn't someone please caress my empty contours?
胸の鼓動に突き飛ばされて 転がり出た愛の言葉
Pushed on by the beating in my chest, these words of love rolled out of my mouth.
だけど困ったな 答えがない
But no one answers them, and I don't know what to do.
宿命に禍(まが)れた 北極星が燃えてる
Chosen by destiny, the northern star is burning bright.
君を掠め盗(と)っしって濁らせた
Though it snatched you away from me into the sooty darkness,
なのに可憐に笑うトコ 好きだったよ
you continued to smile so gracefully. I loved that part of you.
君がいないなら 意味なくなうから
If you are gone, then there's no meaning left to life.
人はみな 消えればいい
I don't care if everyone disappeared.
愛がなくなれば 心だって要らないから この世界も 消えてしまえ
If my love is gone, then I have no more use for my heart. This world can just disappear.
ずっと苦しかった
I was always in pain.
命がけの出会い
I would risk my life for that first time we met.
もがくように夢見た
I dreamt as if I were struggling to breathe.
闇雲に手を伸ばした その胸に訊きたかった
I reached my hands out blindly. I wanted to listen to your heartbeat.
君と虹かけたかった
I wanted to build a rainbow with you.
誰か夜明けの感情で ぎゅっと抱いてくれないか
Wouldn't someone please embrace me tightly with daybreak's sentimentality.
夢の軌道に弾かれて 飛び散るだけの愛の涙
Tears of love that scatter as they are repelled by orbits of dreams will do.
それが剥き出しの痛みでもいい
Their painful flow is just fine for me.
宿命に呼び戻された 北極星が泣いてる
Called back by destiny, the northern star is crying.
どうせ迷路生き抜くなら 君を尽きるまで愛して死にたいよ
If I have to survive in this labyrinth anyway, I want to die loving you to my last breath.
そして始まるのだ 命がけの終わり
And it will begin, the finale I will risk my life for.
戦うように愛した
I loved as if I were fighting to survive.
あー
Ah...
何処まで往こうか
Where should I go?
ネイビーな夜空に映る 過去の自分
My past self is reflected in the navy night sky.
夢見がちだった
I was always daydreaming.
見たくないモノ 照らすハイビームに
In the high beams illuminating things I didn't want to see,
走る焦燥感
a rushing sense of urgency
跳ね除けて前へ往けば
pushes me to press forward.
信号は全色を 無くし消えた
The traffic lights lost all their colors and vanished.
確かめたい この道が繋う場所を
I want to confirm where this road leads.
深く、深く紺になる
Deep, deep into navy blue,
夜を往ける この加速度
traveling through the night at this acceleration.
光さえ超えてゆける程に
To the point of surpassing even light,
強く、強く踏み込んで
stepping down strongly, ever more strongly,
僕は駈ける ただ真っ直ぐに
I run forward, straight ahead,
譲れない想いを抱いて
holding onto unyielding feelings.
あー 久しぶりの3D我が家だー
Ah, it's been a while in my 3D home!
せっかくの3Dなので 渾身の1発ギャグをお願いします！
Since it's a 3D stream, please give us your best one-liner gag!
えっ？一発ギャグですか？
Eh? A one-liner gag?
せっかくくつろぎ出せたのにだー
Even though I finally got comfortable...
まあでもね、みんなもね、わざわざうちの3D我が家まで遊びに来てくれたわけですから
Well, but you know, everyone went out of their way to come visit my 3D home,
まあみんなが喜んでくれるような
so to do something that will make everyone happy...
じゃあ、せっかくなんで一発ギャグやらせていただきますか！
Well then, since we have the chance, let me do a one-liner gag!
それでは、えー参ります。大神ミオの一発ギャグシリーズー！
Well then, um, here I go. Ookami Mio's one-liner gag series!
マグロっ！ピチピチピチピチ…！
Tuna! Flop, flop, flop... !
なんだ…今のいったい。落ちた、落ちたのか？
What was that just now? Did I fall?
まぐろは前に見たので別の1発ギャグお願いします！
I've seen the tuna one before, so please give me a different one-liner gag!
えっ？なんだよ…
Eh? What is this...
なんかわかんないけど…まぐろ、まぐろじゃダメなのかよー！
I don't really get it, but... is tuna no good?!
仕方ないな、じゃあちょっと、うーん考えさせていただきますが、そうですね、やっぱり動物シリーズがいいかなと思うので
Oh well, then... I think an animal series would be good, so
では、えーっと大神ミオの一発ギャグシリーズー！
Now then, um, Ookami Mio's one-liner gag series!
えーっと、じゃあ、やらせていただきます。
Um, I'll do it.
トドっ！オウオウオウオウ…！
Sea lion! Ow, ow, ow... !
あー 久しぶりの3D我が家だー
Ah, it's been a while in my 3D home!
せっかくの3Dなので 渾身の1発ギャグをお願いします！
Since it's a 3D stream, please give us your best one-liner gag!
えっ？一発ギャグですか？
Eh? A one-liner gag?
せっかくくつろぎ出せたのにだー
Even though I finally got comfortable...
まあでもね、みんなもね、わざわざうちの3D我が家まで遊びに来てくれたわけですから
Well, but you know, everyone went out of their way to come visit my 3D home,
まあみんなが喜んでくれるような
so to do something that will make everyone happy...
じゃあ、せっかくなんで一発ギャグやらせていただきますか！
Well then, since we have the chance, let me do a one-liner gag!
それでは、えー参ります。大神ミオの一発ギャグシリーズー！
Well then, um, here I go. Ookami Mio's one-liner gag series!
マグロっ！ピチピチピチピチ…！
Tuna! Flop, flop, flop... !
行きます
Here I go.
よ。また落とすんじゃないだろうな。
Whoa, I hope I don't drop it again.
えーと
Umm...
行きます。
Here I go.
とどっ お お お お お お お
Sto— whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa!
無限ループって怖いね。
Infinite loops are scary.
えっ？ 怖くないの？ なんで2階に流れた今？
Huh? Not scary? Why did it stream to the second floor just now?
落ちた先が まだ自宅だったね。
The place I fell was still my home.
あっ でもよかったね 今度2周目の世界線ではステージに辿りつけたよみお。
Ah, but good thing in the second-loop worldline we managed to reach the stage, Mio.
なるほど。
I see.
はい。ここに辿り着くまでに、あのループで2 なんかも落ちてたってこと？
Yes. Up until reaching here, in that loop, you fell multiple times?
そうそうそうそうそう。
That's right, exactly.
ええー！
Ehh?!
じゃあ あそこのループに閉じ込められたうちもいるってこと？
So does that mean there's also a me trapped in that loop?
そうだね。
That's right.
壊すきだろ！ 壊すすぎだろ！
You're gonna break it! You're overdoing it!
閉じ込められたみおが頑張って出てこようとしてるかもしれないけども、このみおはステージにこれました。
The trapped Mio might be trying hard to come out, but this Mio made it to the stage.
なるほど。
I see.
そう。
Right.
というわけで 皆さん、あ、アイドルステージに帰ってきましたよー！
So everyone, ah, we've returned to the idol stage!
おかえり ただいまー！
Welcome back, I'm home!
みお一周してくるくるくるってやって、アイドルっしょ！みそらみそらもっと！
Mio spin a circle round and round, like an idol! Misora Misora more!
かわいいかよー！
So cute!
いや なかなかね、アイドル衣装ね、切る機会ないから
Well, you don't often get to wear idol outfits, so...
本当だよー。
That's true.
あ、今日接近カメラないのやつらかったなー！
Ah, it sucked that there was no close-up camera today!
そんなのもありましたね。
There was stuff like that too.
そうだ 接近カメラね 欲しかったね。がち恋距離ないんですか カメラさん。
Right, I wanted a close-up camera. Isn't there a "gachikoi distance"? Camera-san?
がち恋用のがち恋距離ないんですか？ うちが近づいたほうがいいのかな？
Isn't there a gachikoi distance? Should I get closer?
いや、どうなんだ？ カメラさんないんですか顔アップ。
Well, I wonder? Camera-san, isn't there a face close-up?
え、それやば！
Eh, that's dangerous!
それやばみお！
That's dangerous, Mio!
みんな 見てるー。
Everyone's watchingー.
それはかわいいみお。
That's cute, Mio.
近づいた！
She got close!
え、待って待って、恥ずかしいのでちょっとそんな
Eh, wait wait, it's embarrassing so a bit like that...
そんなことない、そんなことない
No such thing, no such thing
サムホールもっとクリームついてんだろ、見せろ見せろ、やめてやめて
Thumb hole has cream attached, show me show me, stop stop
サムホールをクローズアップしてよ！
Close up on the thumb hole!
ついてなーい！
Nothing attached!
サムホールも食べたみお。
Mio ate the thumb hole too.
確かにサムホール食べた。けっこう重いね、やっぱね。
True, ate the thumb hole. It's pretty heavy, as expected.
本当だよ、みんな今のスクショした？
Right, did everyone take a screenshot just now?
今のはちょっとがち恋距離っていうかもう接触距離だよ。
That just now wasn't just gachikoi distance, it's contact distance.
じゃあもう接触！
So contact!
接触距離！助かる！接触距離助かる！助かる 助かる
Contact distance! Lifesaver! Contact distance is a lifesaver! Lifesaver lifesaver!
さあみおみお、なんと次で最後の曲？
Now Mio Mio, is the next song the last one?
いや、そうなんだよね。
Yeah, that's right.
やだー！
Nooo!
延長しろ！
Extend it!
燃えるんじゃねえ！
Don't burn out!
というわけで、えっと、まあ最後の1曲なんですけれど、まあ最後はね、ちょっとね、フブキにも一緒に歌ってもらおうかなと思って。
So, um, well, it's the last song, but for the last one, I thought I'd have Fubuki sing along with me.
あ、じゃあ邪魔しない程度に。
Ah, then to the extent that I don't get in the way.
まあ愛の手をね、得意だって言ってるから
Well, you said you're good at call-and-response, so...
そうですね、愛の手を、程よい愛の手を、うん、お願いします。
That's right, please give moderate call-and-response, yeah, please.
はーい！
Okay!
というわけで皆さん、あの 何怒ってるんですか？
So everyone, what are you mad about?
ちょっとね、最後の曲になりますが、えっと聞いてくれると嬉しいです。
Well, it'll be the last song, um, I'd be happy if you'd listen.
ちょっと喉のあたりとかもしてますけれども、え、最後は、夢見る空へで締めたいと思います。
My throat's a bit rough, but I'd like to close with "Yumemiru Sora e".
では、お水がかりありがとう。
Well then, water delivery, thank you.
ラストウォーター！
Last water!
サンキューサンキューサンキュー！
Thank you thank you thank you!
えーと、はい、では夢見る空へです。よろしくお願いします！
Umm, yes, well, it's "Yumemiru Sora e". Please look forward to it!
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our overlapping hands tightly without letting go
行くよ 夢見る空へ
Let's go, to the dream-seeing sky
最後だけど みんな盛り上がっていこう！
Even though it's the end, everyone let's get hyped!
窓越しに見上げた とても小さな空 ここで出会えたのは 数え切れない奇跡
The sky I looked up at through the window, a very small sky. Meeting here was countless miracles.
繰り返した一歩が きらめきを繋いで 星のような笑顔 道引いた
Each repeated step connected the sparkle, leading our smiles like stars.
Say, BYE-BYE みんなの声が 力になる Say, BYE-BYE Stage ここでそれぞれ 描くもの
Say, BYE-BYE, everyone's voices become strength. Say, BYE-BYE Stage, what each of us draws here
それぞれ目指すもの それぞれ願い合った夢へ
What each aims for, toward the dreams we wished for each other
重ねた手は ぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our overlapping hands tightly without letting go
一人じゃない 描き出すと決めて
Deciding to draw it, not alone
おとなしくまっすぐに 行くよ 今は
I'll go straight and obediently for now,
夢見る空へ
toward the sky of my dreams.
笑い合ったことや 月日そうにないわだかまり
The times we shared laughs, and lingering grievances...
想い出いっぱいなのだに あっという間の日々
Even with so many memories, the days passed in a flash.
上書きじゃなくて 名前つけて保存
Instead of overwriting, I'll save them with a name—
どれも全部大事で生き切れる
they're all precious and help me live fully.
ワン、ツー、スリー、フォア！ みんなのためが力になる
One, two, three, four! Everyone's support becomes my strength!
オー、アイ、オー！ 共でにぎやかすぎるくらい
Oh, I, oh! Together, we're almost too lively—
笑顔がもつまらない 想いはふくらんでいく
smiles are endless as feelings swell up inside.
重ねた手をぎゅっとかみしめた
Clasping our intertwined hands tightly,
一人ひとり違う声で 歌おう声は広がる
singing with each of our unique voices, the song spreads out.
風を感じたら まっすぐに
When you feel the breeze, go straight ahead—
行くよ 今は 夢見る空へ
I'm going now, toward the sky of my dreams!
憧れを手を伸ばし つかみ取ったその光が
Reaching out for my aspirations, the light I grasped—
いつの日か また誰かの憧れに変わる 繋げよう
will someday become someone else's dream too. Let's connect it!
みんな今日はいっぱいありがとう ちょっと失敗しちゃったところもあったけど このステージすごーく楽しかったよ
Thank you all so much today! I made a few mistakes, but this stage was so much fun!
一人ひとり違う色で 描き出すトキメキ
painting our excitement with each of our unique colors.
出会えたすべてに ありがとうを
Saying thank you for everything we've encountered—
奇跡だって起こし続け ずっとそばにいるよ
we'll keep creating miracles and stay by your side forever!
行くよ 今は 夢見る空へ ありがとう！
I'm going now, toward the sky of my dreams! Thank you!
というわけで、以上、大神ミオ 2周年記念 3Dライブでした！ありがとうございました！
And with that, that concludes Ookami Mio's 2nd Anniversary 3D Live! Thank you!
めっちゃよかった！ふぶきも愛の手ありがとうね！
It was so good! Fubuki, thank you for the cheering too!
いやもう完全に心はミオファでしたね！
Honestly, my heart was completely Miofa!
もうふぶきはずっとデビュー当初から、うん、本当この2年間ずっと一緒に歩いてきたから
Fubuki has been walking together with me right from the debut for two whole years.
1周年記念の時も、マイクが…1周年の時も、一緒に放送に出てくれて
Even at the 1st anniversary—the microphone... you appeared on stream with me.
そう、2周年も絶対一緒に出てほしいなって思ってて、ありがとう！
Yeah, I really wanted you to be here for the 2nd anniversary too. Thank you!
よしよしよししてくれる？ 本当にいいの！？
Will you give me headpats? Are you really sure?!
え、空気だけで…よしよしよしよしよし！よしよしよしよしよしよしよしよしよし！
Just in spirit... pat pat pat pat!
テクニシャンなんだよな
You're quite the technician, aren't you?
というわけでね、ライブは終わりなんですけど、ミオからの告知が！ある？
And with that, the live is over, but Mio has an announcement!
ざわざわざわ…みなさん、ちょっと前からも言っててたんですけどもね、なんと、え、2周年記念ボイス発売されます！やったー！
Everyone, I've been talking about this for a bit, but my 2nd Anniversary Voice Pack is on sale!
ボイスだけなんですか？…グッズセットなどもご用意させていただいております！
We've prepared so many goods and merchandise sets that it almost feels too good!
なに！？なんだこれはミオ！
What?! What is this, Mio?!
あのちょっとはずかしいですけど、あの、あのすいません、あの結婚するのか！
Um, it's a bit embarrassing, but... are we getting married?!
なんじゃこの読みみおは！許さんぞミオ！ちょっとあの、よみみおじゃないですけれども
What kind of "Yomimio" is this?! I won't forgive you, Mio!
今回イズミ彩パパがなんと描き下ろしでこちらのイラストを描いていただきました！
For this, Isumi-sai papa drew this brand-new illustration for us!
イエーーーイ！
Yay!
その内容が描き下ろしキャンバスアートって何ですか？
What is this canvas art of the drawn illustration?
そうなんです。このね描き下ろしイラストのキャンバスアートが、
That's right. This canvas art featuring the new illustration...
ええとですねボイスのグッズのセットでついてきます。
...comes bundled with the voice and merchandise set.
なるほど。でその中身はミオがいつも見てるお守りって何？
I see. And what is this "protective charm Mio always looks at"?
そうなんです。あのですね、あの、あ、ミコチがヨメーーって言ってる。
That's right. You see, um... ah, Mikochi is shouting "Wife!".
あのですね、実はですね、あのうちが、お守りが欲しいなと思いまして、それで、あの、ちょっとね、うちのお守りをミオのお守りを作りました。
Actually, you see, I thought I wanted an amulet, so I went ahead and made "Mio's Amulet" based on my own.
なんだって！お守り！
What?! An amulet?!
そうなんです。あとは、あのハンドタオル、え、待って、ミオファの証ってあるの？証なの？
That's right. And also, a hand towel... Wait, is there a "Proof of Miofa"? Is that a proof?
いや、まあまああの、まあちょっとミオファっぽいデザインにしたのよ。
Well, you know, I made the design feel very "Miofa-like."
本当に？え、気になるデザイン！
Really? Wow, I'm curious about the design!
そうなの。デザインもねちょっとね、うちがイチから手がけまして
That's right. I designed it completely from scratch myself.
本当に？すごい！すごいシンプルなすけど、こういうのだったらみんな持ち歩ける、あ、これだ、はい！
Really? Amazing! It's super simple, so anyone can easily carry it around. Ah, this is it, yes!
ええ、めっっちゃかわいい！みんな持ってる！
Wow, super cute! Everyone's holding one!
いやこんなんだったら可愛いかなと思って作ったデザインなんだけど
I made it thinking this kind of design would be super cute.
なるほど。であ、ミオファの証のハンドタオルかわいい！
I see. And ah, the "Proof of Miofa" hand towel is so cute!
いやそうなんだよね。結構シンプルだね。
Yeah, exactly. It's pretty simple.
いやそうなんだよね。よく使えるかなと思って。
Yeah, I thought it'd be great for everyday use.
でさらにえ、ミオと一緒にお出かけキーホルダーということでSNS風キーホルダーだってしてる？
And furthermore, um, it's an "Outing Keychain with Mio," styled like social media. Did you know?
知ってる知ってる！これってさ、あれだよね、背景とかさってさ、
I know, I know! This is like, you know, the background and stuff...
あ、そうそうそうそうそう！透けてるんだよねそこが。ええーー！
Ah, exactly, exactly, exactly! It's see-through right there. Wow!
デートじゃん！いやそうなんですよ。
It's like a date! Yeah, exactly.
ちょっとミオとねデートキーホルダーじゃ。いやあ、デート、うん、ま、デート、許さん！
It's a "dating with Mio" keychain. Wait, dating? Hmm, well, dating—no way!
そしてなんと！出た！これと、これはビッグゴートさん？
And what's more! It's here! And this is Big God-san?
そうなんです。オリジナルタロットカードと申しますが、
That's right. They're called original tarot cards,
ま、で、あの、これですね、あの3枚だけなんです。
but you see, there are only 3 cards in this set.
あのあの、大アルカナ何枚だと思うんで？あのあの、ビッグゴットミオさんは大アルカナ何枚ありますか？
Um, um, how many Major Arcana cards do you think there are? Big God Mio-san, how many Major Arcana are there?
ええと、ま全部で21枚。でこれ、3枚ずつしか出ないんですか？
Um, well, 21 in total. And these only come in packs of 3?
何年かかりますか？ええと、そうですね、10年後にすべてが揃うという計算となっております。
How many years will that take? Um, well, the calculation is that you'll complete the set in 10 years.
どこかのあの毎月買あれみたいな！え、これ？
Like some monthly subscription thing! Huh, this?
ま、まあ、まあ、ちょっとシリーズ化じゃないですけど、1年に1回はちょっと少なすぎだから、定期的に出して、3か月に1回のエンスにするとか、
Well, it's not quite a series, but once a year is a bit too little, so releasing them regularly, like once every 3 months...
うんとね、まあ一気にどっかでドカーンとね、枚数を出すんじゃなくて、いやそうなのよ、これはね、ちょっとね、作っていただきまして。
Instead of dropping a huge batch all at once... yeah, exactly, I had them make it like this.
まあ、実実は今回の3枚で、ちょっと右側にあるちょっとタイガーをね、手なづけてるやつとかあるんで。で、力。力のカードね。本当だ、力のカードを感じますなあ。
Actually, in these three, the one on the right where she's taming a tiger is there. Strength. The Strength card. True, I can feel the power of the Strength card.
そうなんです。ちなみに、え、ボイスってどんなんなんだいい？
That's right. By the way, um, what kind of voice packs are there?
あ、気になるぞ。きちゃいますそれ。
Ah, I'm curious. Here it comes!
考そこそこなんか、タイ中台本みたいなのやってるなと思ってたみおん。
I thought she was working on some big script all this time, Mion.
え、ボイスちょっと気になりますよ。だってさ、キャンバスアートがこれですよ。もしやそれに続きありますか？
Eh, I'm a bit curious about the voice. Because look, the canvas art is this. By any chance, is there a sequel to that?
あの、ちょっとあの、今回ですね、あのあの、ウェ、ウェディングボイスってやつで！ちょっとちょっと！とっちゃっち！
Um, well, this time, it's called... a wedding voice! Wait, wait! Totchatchi!
え、あの、多分それでもうちょっと、ちょっとなんでそんな隠れるんですか？
Eh, um, probably with that... wait, why are you hiding so much?
いや、それで多分パパが、あのこんなイラストを描いてくれたのかなって。
Well, maybe that's why papa drew this kind of illustration for me.
ウェディングって申しませ、そうなんです。ウェディングボイス！え、結婚するのか！
Wedding voice, you say? That's right. Wedding voice! Eh, we're getting married?!
また三者様現れた！いや白神のみこだ！
Another Sanja-san appeared! No, it's Shirakami Mikoda!
というわけで、皆さんね、よかったらうちと結婚してください。
And with that, everyone, if you'd like, please marry me.
ははははは！照れないで！照れないで！照れないで！
Hahaha! Don't be shy! Don't be shy! Don't be shy!
ええと、で、まああのこちらのですね、あのボイスとグッズ、全部を、あの、買ってくれた、ま、セットで買ってくれた方には、
Um, and well, for those who buy the voice and merchandise set altogether,
特典として、はい。ええと、もう1個のやつを、と、きますかな？はい。何が出るんだ？出るかな？どうですかね？
as a bonus, yes. We'll include another item, right? What will it be? Will it come out? What do you think?
はい。ええこちらがですね、なんとイズミサイパパが、え、サブンで、え、笑顔のみおも描いてくれたので、これをですね、あのポストカードにさせていただいて、こちらにうちが、え、直筆のサインを、え、書いて、ちょっとメッセージとかも書いて、お送りしようかなと、思ってます。
Yes. This here is... Isumi-sai papa generously drew a smiling Mio for us too, so we're making this into a postcard, on which I'll write my direct autograph and some messages, and send it to you all!
え？笑顔の、何？あの笑顔の？え、誰に向けた笑顔の？あのそれはね、ミお！
Eh? A smiling... what? That smiling one? Eh, who is that smile directed at? Well, Mio!
いやどなん、その、このうち、うちとすぐね、みたいなさ。いや、なんかこう、結婚してくれてありがとうみたいな感じなのかな？
I mean, like, "Thank you for marrying me," something like that?
そういう？ま、ちょっとうちもまだ結婚したことないからさ、そういう感情的なものは分からないんだけどさ、でもなんかすごく嬉しそうだね。
Like that? Well, I've never been married either, so I don't really understand those emotional things, but she looks super happy.
ええ、これいつから購入できるんですか？あ、負けたくないの。負けたくない！既婚戦争に
Eh, when can we buy this? Ah, I don't want to lose. I don't want to lose the marriage war!
時間を教えてくれないか
Won't you tell me the time?
実は直近決戦って今回ないんです
Actually, there's no recent decisive battle this time.
え、本当に？
Eh, really?
買えばもらえる？
Can we get it if we buy?
応募者全員サービス？
An all-applicants service?
あ、そうです！
Ah, that's right!
よっしゃー！みんな！
Awesome, everyone!
落ちるぞ！
It's falling!
あのミオファの森は平和でいけないなと思って
I thought Miofa's forest needs to be peaceful.
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
よかったみんな！数量限定じゃないぞ！
Yay, everyone! It's not limited quantity!
というわけでね、いつからですか？こちら。
Anyway, when does it start? This.
あ、一応あの本日
Ah, basically, today—
本日の、えっと、10時半からの… 10時半から？
Today, um, starting at 10:30... From 10:30?
あ、アップ！
Ah, open!
なので、配信！
So, stream!
はい！
Yes!
なのでちょっとあの、URLなどもね、あの、Twitterなどでね。
So, um, URLs and stuff, on Twitter too.
はい！
Yes!
あ、なんか放送の概要欄に、あ、もう出てるかな？
Ah, it's already in the broadcast description box?
もう貼ってくれてますね。
They've already posted it.
おおさすが！
Oh, as expected!
ご購入できるのは12時半…あ、10時半から？
You can purchase from 12:30... ah, 10:30?
あ、そうです！
Ah, yes, that's right!
そうです！
That's right!
もうあのゲートは開いてるんですけど、購入は10時半からとなっております。
The gate is already open, but purchases start at 10:30.
なるほど！
I see!
えー、ちょっとすみません、あのアップパネルの方もう一度見せてもらっていいですか？
Um, excuse me, can you show the up panel again?
読みミオのパネルの方のイラストをちょっと、いいですか？
The illustration on Yomio's panel, please?
あー、ちょっと恥ずかしい。
Ah, a bit embarrassing.
グッズ詳細じゃない方の1枚目のやつですかね？
Is it the first one, not the merch details?
ちょっと、もう一度出してもらっていいですか？
Could you put it up again?
この顔！ねえ！この顔おかあさんニコはずるいじゃん！
This face! Hey! This face, Mom's smile is so unfair!
え、しかもさ、これ下で結んでるねミオ。
Eh, and look, Mio is tying it at the bottom.
いや、そうなんだよ！めずらしい髪型でしょ？
Yeah, that's right! It's an unusual hairstyle, right?
そうそうそうそう！いつもせばぴょんぴょん跳ねてるけどさ、なんかちょっとショートっぽい感じがしていいよね、この髪型。
Yeah, yeah! It usually bounces around, but this short-ish feel is nice.
なんて言うんだろ、かわいい！ちょっと次髪型さん、ちょっと下結びとかどう大白上にお送りしたりしないかい？
What should I call it, cute! Next time, maybe a low tie or something for Shirakami?
これこれね？
This one, right?
そうそうそう！この髪型ね？ねえ！かわいいめっちゃ！
Yeah, yeah! This hairstyle? Hey! So cute!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、よかったみんなね、戦争ないでね、前回も、はい。平和、平和です。
Right, good thing there's no war, everyone, last time too, yes. Peace, it's peace.
平和ですけど、ミオは、わたさんか？白上の足から、降りにこい！
It's peace, but Mio, you're not passing? Come down from Shirakami's feet!
えー、白上を倒さなきゃいけないらしいので、みなさん頑張ってください。フブーラになるぞ！
Umm, apparently we have to defeat Shirakami, so everyone do your best. Become Fubura!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、えー、みなさん本当に今日は、あのー、集まってくださり、そして最後まで見て下さり、本当にありがとうございます！そしてフブキも最後まで見守りどうもありがとー！
So, um, thank you all so much for gathering today and watching until the end! And Fubuki, thank you for watching over us until the end!
はーい！
Yessir!
あ、ちょっと、ちょっとしゃがみから１個いいかい？コメント欄のみんなとやりたいことがある。
Ah, wait, can I do one thing from a squat? There's something I want to do with everyone in the chat.
じゃみんな、いいか、準備いいか？白上と同じ文章打ってね！いくよー！
Alright everyone, ready? Type the exact same sentence as Shirakami! Here we go!
みおー！2周年おめでとー！
Mio! Happy 2nd Anniversary!
あーりがとー！いえーい！
Thank you! Yay!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ちょっとね、時間、時間が来るからコメント来るかな？コメント、はーって見て終わりたい。ありがとー！
Time is running out, will comments come? I want to look at the comments and finish. Thank you!
というわけで、みんなの2周年おめでとうのコメントを見ながら幸せな気持ちで終わりたいと思います。
With that, I'd like to end on a happy note reading everyone's 2nd anniversary congratulatory comments.
みなさん本当に今日はどうもありがとうございました！また何かしらの形でリベンジさせてください！おねがいします！
Thank you all so much for today! Please let us get our revenge in some form again! Please!
というわけで、おつみおー！ありがとねー！
With that, Otsumio! Thank you!